earthtechling.com 2011-12-10

# Privacy Policy | EarthTechling

EarthTechling, LLC is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following statement to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of the EarthTechling Website. The EarthTechling Website is owned and operated by EarthTechling, LLC.

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by e-mail at [privacypolicy@earthtechling.com](mailto:privacypolicy@earthtechling.com).

 **SUMMARY**  
Our primary goal in collecting user information is to enhance your experience on our Website. We use aggregated (gathered up data across all user accounts) information to develop content targeted to users’ interests and to better the user experience. EarthTechling is committed to your privacy and will not share any personal information with any third party at any time, unless required to do so by law.

 **WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVERS**

This privacy policy covers the website EarthTechling.com.  Other sites linked to from this Website have their own privacy statements which can be viewed on those sites.

 **GATHERING OF INFORMATION**  
****

**Voluntary Submission**  
EarthTechling does not collect personally identifying information about any individual EarthTechling Website user except when knowingly provided by such individual. For example, we may ask you for information, such as your e-mail address, zip code and the country in which you are viewing the Website when you register, to customize personalization applications (if any), to enter a contest or complete a survey. You always have the option not to provide the information we request. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you can still visit most of the EarthTechling Website, but you may be unable to access certain options and services.

 **Cookies**  
A cookie is a data file that certain websites write to your computer’s hard drive when you visit such sites. A cookie file can contain information, such as a user identification code, that the site uses to track the pages you have visited. EarthTechling uses cookies to track user traffic patterns throughout the EarthTechling Website and to remember your passwords and video plug-in preferences so that you don’t have to reset them each time you visit the Website. We use this data on an anonymous basis and we do not correlate this information with personal data of any user. Business partners of EarthTechling and vendors providing hosting and other services for EarthTechling, as well as advertisers who contract directly with a third-party service to serve their advertisements, may set their own cookies which may collect similar anonymous information.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to display a warning before accepting a cookie, or to refuse all cookies. However, if you choose to disable the receipt of cookies from our Website, you may not be able to use certain features of the site.

 **Browser Level Information**  
EarthTechling Web servers automatically collect information about a site user’s IP address, browser type and the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on the Website or not) and which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on the Website or not) by reading this information from the user’s browser (information provided by every user’s browser). This information is collected in a database and used – in an aggregated, anonymous manner – in our internal analysis of traffic patterns within our Website. This information is automatically logged by most Websites. EarthTechling also uses a third party to collect information, including through the use of web beacons.

 **Use of Information**  
Our primary goal in collecting user information is to enhance your experience on our Website.

 **To Target Content**  
To develop content targeted to your interests, we use aggregated user information to determine which areas of our Website users prefer based upon traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but instead how well each page or content area performs overall.

 **To Provide Interactive Communications From EarthTechling**  
To enhance your experience we may provide you with interactive communications, such as electronic newsletters, to the e-mail address that you provide to us. Such interactive communications are provided only to those users who have expressly provided us with their permission to receive them as part of their user profile.

From time to time we may provide e-mails highlighting new features, promotions or contests on the Website to those users who have expressly provided us with their permission to send such communications as part of their user profile.

 **Sharing of Information**  
We respect the privacy of our users and shall not disclose or distribute our user list to any third party, nor shall we permit anyone else to do so.

 **Aggregate, Anonymous Information With Advertisers**  
EarthTechling derives the majority of its revenue from advertising and sharing information is essential to keeping our services affordable to users. In order to attract and retain advertisers we use the aggregated, anonymous information that we gather to describe our services to business associates and to assist our advertisers and sponsors to better understand our audience. We do not disclose personally identifying information about our users to these parties.

 **As Necessary to Provide Services to You**  
We may hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of newsletter mailings, or performing statistical analysis of our services. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service. These companies are subject to agreements that require them to maintain the confidentiality of your information and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

 **As Required By Law**  
EarthTechling may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on EarthTechling or to protect and defend the rights or property of EarthTechling.

 **Security**  
Your information is stored on EarthTechling’s servers located in the United States. We use procedural and technical safeguards to protect your personal information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access and disclosure to protect your privacy, including encryption, “firewalls” and Secure Socket Layers. We treat data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. However, “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet.

 **Privacy of Children**

 _The EarthTechling Website is not intended for use by persons under the age of thirteen._ Individuals who are under the age of thirteen are expressly prohibited from submitting to EarthTechling or posting to the site any personally identifiable information about themselves.  Kids under 13: Do not send any information about yourself to us – including information such as your name, address, or email address.

THIS WEBSITE SPECIFICALLY DENIES ACCESS TO ANY INDIVIDUAL THAT IS COVERED BY THE CHILD ONLINE PRIVACY ACT (COPA) OF 1998.  We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13.  In the event that we learn we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as possible.  
****

**How to Contact Us**  
If you have any questions regarding our privacy statement, please feel free to contact us by e-mail at [privacypolicy@earthechling.com](mailto:privacypolicy@earthechling.com).  We read every message submitted and try to reply promptly to every one.

 **How Will I Know if the Privacy Policy Is Changed?**  
This Policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically.
